Quality Assurance Engineer

Dzmitry Slizhou

San Mateo, CA tel: 302-344-4691 email: d.slizhou@gmail.com

Professional Summary:

Software Quality Assurance Engineer with 6 years of experience in testing Robotic software, Web-based and mobile applications. Expertise conduction various tests, such as performance, networking, API, regression, functional, UI, including developing and implementing test plans and test cases. Solid understanding and practical experience of system development life cycle (SDLC) principals and experience working with Agile software development methodologies. Work knowledge of Windows, Linux and Mac OS environment. Experience with test case and defect repositories such as Jira and Bugzilla. Able to work under tight deadlines and rapidly changing priorities. Work well independently as well as in a team. Well organized and capable to quickly learn new technical skills.

Technical Summary:

Platforms: Ubuntu 16.04/18.04, Windows 10, MacOS Programming: HTML, CSS, XML, SQL, Java, Python

Mobile Platforms: iOS, Android OS

Robotic: Raspberry Pi, ROS (Lidar mapping and navigation), Terra Term, LogReplay

Database: MySQL 8.0

Professional Experience:

OA Technician

Amazon Lab126 via Latitude36, Mountain View, CA

June 2020 - Present

Testing Computer Vision component on Amazon Alexa devices

Contribute to the test plans design, test cases, scenarios, scripts and procedures

Execute regression, bug verification, and performance testing includes KPI for CPU usage, memory consumption, latency measurement etc.

Create scripts in Python to speed up the testing process, utilizing Git to push scripts to code review

Utilize GIT and Amazon internal build distributions tools Pipelines for continuous integration and distribution

Utilize KATS on Ubuntu 16.04 to run automated tests

Train new members including offshore team located in India

Report the issues in Jira, triage them and track until closed

Participate in sprint planning and bug triage meetings

Utilize ADB for device testing

Tools: JIRA, TestRail, ADB, GIT, Python.

Quality Assurance Engineer

Neato Robotics, Newark, CA

August 2018 – June 2020

Neato Robotics designs autonomous robot vacuums with intelligent laser navigation, smart home and mobile applications support

Performed testing of the software and firmware on Neato Robotic and Vorwerk robots

Performed testing of native Neato and Kobold mobile applications on iOS and Android

Conducted specific product-related tests such as navigation, connectivity, sensors verification, Wi-Fi (802.11 ac),

functional-regression, including SQLite database testing

Utilized Python and Shell scrips for logs parsing and analysis

Conducted localization testing for Neato Mobile app against 22 European and Asian languages

Transitioned test cases from Polarion and MS Excel into X-Ray

Set testing environment for up to 50 units. Deployed proper generation of firmware and software builds Used Jira to report issues. Used Microsoft SharePoint to document test data and robot behavior Utilized Tera Term Terminal to communicate with robot API

Tools: JIRA, Xray, Polarion, ADB, Tera Term, Microsoft SharePoint, LogReplay, MS Excel.

Quality Assurance Engineer

June 2017 – August 2018

Practical Net, Los Altos, CA

Participated in testing of Web-based application

Performed manual test execution (Ad-hoc, Functional, UAT, System and Regression Testing)

Utilized Postman for API testing, Charles Proxy for networking logs

Used SQL and sub languages to query MySQL

Sent status reports to QA manager

Used JIRA as a bug tracking tool

Tools: ADB, JIRA, MS Excel, MySQL, Postman, Charles Proxy

Software QA Tester

December 2015 - May 2017

QAUBER, Santa Clara, CA

Tested Web/ Mobile applications that connect software development companies with professional software testers

Identified and investigated GUI, functional and technical defects. Filed detailed bug reports utilizing JIRA with screen captures, videos, and attached logs using ADB logcat, Charles Proxy. Verified fixed bugs

Used Browsers Developers Tools to debug websites and evaluate HTML, CSS code changes. Performed browser (EI, FF, Chrome, Safari) compatibility testing

Created and managed test cases in TestRail Test Case Management Software

Performed functional, exploratory, UI, regression, sanity, ad-hoc, and smoke testing

Tools: JIRA, TestRail, Skype, Android Studio, ADB, Charles Proxy.

Education & Training:

Certificate: Test Automation using Selenium with Java. Computer Educational Center of Daly City, California, 2020

[PCEP-30-01] PCEP - Certified Entry-Level Python Programmer. OpenEDG Python Institute

Certificate: Build Websites from Scratch. Codecademy. 2018

B.E. Fire Safety. State Engineering University. Minsk, Belarus, 2003